good evening ladies and gentlemen and a
very warm welcome to icsa Lombard
General Insurance company limiteds Q3
and 9mon FY 2025 earnings conference
call from the Senior Management we have
with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr gopal balachandran
CFO Mr Girish nyak Chief technology and
health underwriting and claims Mr sandip
Goradia Chief corporate solutions group
Mr Anam singi Chief retail and
government business and Mr G Aurora
Chief underwriting and claims for
Property and
Casualty please note that any statements
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star then zero
on your touchone phone I now hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri MD
and CEO IC Lombard General Insurance
Limited thank you and over to you sir
thank you so
much good evening to each one of you
thank you thank you for joining the
earnings conference call of icsa Lombard
for quarter 3 and 9 months financially
at
2025 at the outset let me wish you all a
very happy new
year as I complete First St in my
current role I'm excited to share
developments we have made together since
we connected on January 16
2024 we outlined our vision of one is
one team building cohesive teams to
leverage synergies and complimentary
strength to talk to tap into new
business
opportunities in this endeavor we
realigned our teams to work
collaboratively under a unified product
and business practice today I'm pleased
to share many of our initiatives such as
one one call center one is one digital
and one one agency have started yielding
results any change of a significant
magnitude requires continuous
reinforcement and we continue to learn
as we co-create an environment conducive
to conducive to growth Innovation and
collaboration Let Me Now update on
update you on industry Trends and
developments that we have witnessed in
the past few months of financial year
2025 for the quarter ended September
2024 as per the data released by mospi
the GDP growth slowed down to 5.4% as
compared to 88.1% in the corresponding
quarter of previous year let me dwell on
certain key data points during last
quarter which can have an impact on GI
industry at Large
on the corporate side the industry is
supporting infrastructure and
constructions like steel cement and
Commercial Vehicle sales winess muted
growth as government spending towards
Capital expend capital expenditure
remains luggage which we also which is
also reflecting in the commercial lines
of General insurance
industry on the auto sector the industry
reported mut growth in quarter 3 of 2025
as per CM with growth in private car at
4 and a half% grow GR in two wheer at 3%
and degrowth in CV at 5% the retail
reimburse as reported by SP has seen
Improvement in the growth on account of
uptic in rural demand With Private Car
growing at 4 5.9% two-wheeler at 12.4%
and CV at
1.6% health insurance continues to be
the fastest growing and largest
contributor of the industry in in the
gdpi mix attracting significant
investment across
stakeholders the bank credit growth also
moderated to 11% due to slowdown in
credit to nbfc segment and unsecured
loans in addition the mfi sector growth
also got adversely impacted due to
structural
changes further as we move towards the
next quarter We Believe infra based
spending lower Insurance penetration
enhanc risk awareness in a conducive
regulatory environment is expected to
have positive impact on General
Insurance Insurance sector over medium
to long term coming to the regulatory
update general insurers are mandated to
recognize premium for long-term product
on a 1 byn basis effective October 1st
2024 as an industry new motor policies
due to long-term TP were recognized on 1
byn basis there is thus there is no
impact on this line of business the
premium under long-term health and other
line of business were recognized in the
year of underwriting itself this change
has an impact on the reporting of health
and other line of business for the
industry for quarter three of financial
year
2025 however this does not impact the
economic value so we continue to
evaluate business opportunities which is
expected to deliver sustained returns to
stakeholders secondly on solvency Norms
The Authority issued guidelines on on
inadmissibility of asset which changes
disallowance of primarily from net basis
to gross basis due to this there a
reduction of 30 basis points in our
solvency ratio as at March 3 as at
December 31st 2024 consequently our
solvency ratio was 2.36 as at December
31st 2024 Which is higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
thus this change does not impact our
growth Journey The General Insurance
Council has represented the matter to
the authority emphasizing the
significant implication of this change
on the solvency position for the
industry players
now coming to the industry growth gross
direct premium income has grown by 99.5%
and 7.8% for quarter three of financial
year 2025 and 9 months Financial year
2025 respectively as published by di
Council excluding crop and massel
segment the industry registered a growth
of
5.7% and 99.1% for quarter 3 Financial
year 2025 and 9 month 2025 respectively
speaking on the specific segments within
the industry during the quarter under
motor insurance the industry GW at 7.6%
for quarter three Financial year 2025
the total numbers of vehicles sold as
per CM data is approximately 3.1 million
Private Car 15 million two wheelers and
1.2 million CV for 9 months Financial
year
2025 the health segment during the
quarter delivered double digit growth
within the group health within this
group health G at 14.6% and Retail
Health View at 6.6% year on year in
quartery financial 2025 further subdue
credit dis verment by financial
institutions has resulted in a slower
growth of Health Business Health Benefit
business the commercial line segment de
at
8.4% within this the fire contined to
deow resisting a degrowth of 22% on
account of pricing pressure we expect
the pricing to improve in the fire
segment in the coming months now
speaking of the underwriting performance
for the industry the com combined ratio
for the industry vers
23.3% from for H1 of 2025 as against
Triple
1.9% for H1 of 2024 largely on account
of increase in expense ratio for the
motor business the industry combined
ratio was turn to 24.8% in H1
financially at 2025 from 11 19.4% in H1
of 2024 I will now speak about the
company's performance across key
business segments during quarter 3
Financial year
2025 the company's gdpi for quarter 3
Financial year 2025 registered a growth
of
4.8% with one by hand accounting Norm
the company registered degrowth of 3% as
again the industry growth of
99.5% during the same period excluding
crop and Mass health the company degre
by 7%
as compared to Industry growth of
5.7% in commercial line segment we
remain cautious due to continued pricing
pressure resulting in degrowth of
8.6% however we continue to maintain a
market share in the segment further we
have maintained our leadership position
in liability and Marine cargo segment in
motor we grew at 9.4% for quarter3
financial year 2025 as against the
industry growth of
7.6% our growth in this segment was driv
by festive lead Auto Sales as well as
old book during this quarter we
sustained a balance portfolio with the
mix of Private Car two wheeler and CV at
52.9 26.7 and 20.4
respectively moving to the health
business during the quarter we GRE at
10.3% for quarter 3 Financial year 2025
and with one byn accounting now we
degree at
4.6% within health our retail Health
segment registered a growth at
44.3% with one by an accounting Norm the
growth was at 19.1% is as against
industry growth of
6.6% during the same period resultantly
we gain market share and Retail Health
reaching 3.2% in quarter 3 Financial
year
2025 as updated updated in our previous
call we continue to invest in product
Innovation and Technology integration
this includes upgrades to elevate
Eventing a super top product activate
booster and travel product trip secure
plus doing the quarter in the group
health employer employee segment we
continue to maintain cautious approach
on account of competitive intensity
resulting in mut growth at 1.1% in
quarter three Financial year
2025 our group other business duw at
1.8% with one byn accounting Norm the
degrowth in this segment was at 33%
during the same
period we continue to harness our
digital capabilities to enhance customer
experience leading to a customer facing
digital business growing at growth of
9.9% constituting 7.4% of our overall
gdpi during the quarter our I take care
app has surpassed 13.2 million user
downloads registering a premium of 64.2
million for quarter 3 Financial year
2025 additionally I would like to
highlight efforts being undertaken
towards improving claims efficiency
across retail line of business our Fifer
partner Network serviced
73.6% of our non OEM claims in quarter 3
Financial year 2025 as again 67.3 in
quarter 3 of financial year
2024 our average claim settlement period
of retail line of business has seen
Improvement it has improved from six
days in financial 2024 to 5 days in 9
month Financial year 2025 for motor OD
and from 5 days in financial year 2024
to 3 days in 9 month Financial year 2025
for health our initiative is s which was
launched in April of 2024 offered an Ong
ground support to over 65,000 customers
across 2,500 hital Network we continue
to monitor our customer feedback from
independent agencies in the form of net
promoter score study on regular basis
our NPS continues to be healthy at 69
and 65 for Financial year 2025 for
health and motor claims respectively
supported by a customer trust in one of
the previous update we discussed on a
Core Business and Technology
transformation project project we
initiated transformation journey of a
health business and have now achieved a
critical Milestone by ruling out a
flagship retail Indemnity product
Elevate on a new code platform going
forward we expect a shorter period of
development of products on a new system
are
we are excited to see this
extending across our product categories
under the health business and Beyond we
firmly believe project will be a key
enabler of a vision of one is one team
as we conclude we have positive and
determined to achieve profitable
outcomes led by multiproduct multi-
distribution strategy focus on product
Innovation data analytics and digital
enhancement with our guiding force of
one is one team I will now request gopal
to take through the financial numbers
for the recent concluded quarter and 9
months thanks sanjie and good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and nine months we have uploaded
the result presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance
numbers with effect from October 1 2024
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byn basis as mandated by the regulator
ends quarter three and 9 months numbers
of this year are not comparable with
prior periods or prior years please also
refer to slide number 15 of our investor
presentation for further details uh on
this the gross direct premium income of
the company was at rupes 2 20 6.23
billion in 9 months of this year as
againsted 187.5 billion in 9 months of
last year a growth of
10.3% as against the industry growth of
7.8% gdpi was R 6214 billion in quarter
3 as against 62.3 billion in quarter 3
last year a degrowth of 3% as againsted
the industry growth of
99.5% on the retail side of the business
GDP of motor was r 31.0 n in quarter 3
as againsted rupes
28.425b for motor segment was rupes 36.4
4 billion as at December 31 2024 as
against 35.13 billion as at September 30
2024 GDP of the segment was 13.16
billion in quarter 325 as against 1.79
billion in quarter 324 registering a
degrowth of 4.6% our agent which
included the point of sale distribution
count was 1 14077 at December 31 2024 up
from 1 lak
33683 as at September 30 2024 GDP of the
commercial line was 4.63 in Q3 this year
as against R 16 billion in Q3 FY 24
registering a degrowth of 8.6%
resultantly the combined ratio was 10
2.9% in 9 month
fi25 as against 103.7 in 9 months last
year the combined ratio was 102.7 in
quarter 3 of the current year as against
13.6% in quarter 3 f524 excluding the
impact of cat losses of rupes .94
billion in 9 months fi25 and rupes 1.37
billion in 9 month f524 the combined
ratio was 102 3% and 10 2.6%
respectively excluding the impact of cat
losses of r54 billion in Q3 fi 24 the
combined ratio was 10
12.3% there were no major catastrophic
losses for Q3 F525 our investment assets
during the quarter Rose to rupes 55.97
billion at December 31 2024 up from
55.57 billion at September 30 2024 our
investment leverage net of borrowings
was 3.76 times as at December 31 2024 as
against 3.91 times at September 30 2024
investment income was at 33.7 billion in
9 months F525 as a againsted rupes 26.5
7 billion in 9 months f524 on a
quarterly basis investment income was
rupes 11.21 billion in Q3 fi25 as a gain
rce 8.57 billion in Q3 fy4 our capital
gains net of impairment in investment
assets today 7.96 billion in 9 months
fi25 as compared to to R 3 95 billion in
9 month f24 capital gains net of
impairment on investment investment
assets to at rupees 2.76 billion in Q3
fi25 as compared to rupes
1.08 billion in Q3
f24 or profit before tax grew by 42.8%
Ates 26.5 3 billion in 9 months fi25 as
against r
18.57% at R 9.6 billion
in Q3 F525 as against R 5.74 billion in
Q3
f524 consequently profit after tax grew
by
42.9% at rupes 19.99 billion in 9 months
fi this year as against rupes 13.99
billion in 9 month
f24 Pat grew by 67.9% Ates 7.24 billion
in Q3 fi25 up from rupes 4.31 billion in
Q3
f524 return on average Equity was 20.8%
in 9 mons this year as against 17.1% in
9 months of the last year the return on
equity for this quarter of the current
year was 21.5% has ganged 15.3% in Q3 fi
24 solvency ratio was at 2.36 times this
is after factoring in the impact of 30
basis points as sanjie had mentioned as
at December 31 2024 as against 2.65
times as at September 30 2024 which
continued to be higher than the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times as I
conclude I would like to state that we
are aligned with our RoR of driving
profitable growth consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders are in the
for Forefront at all times I would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we'll be happy to take
questions that you have thank you thank
you very much we will now begin the
question and answer session anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on their Touchstone telephone if
you wish to remove yourself from the
question Q you may press star and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a
question ladies and gentlemen we will
wait for a moment while the question que
assembles we'll take a first question
from the line of nishin Chate from kotak
institutional equities please go ahead
uh hi uh thanks for taking my question
and uh you know congrats for a good set
of numbers uh you know just a little bit
of commentary on the motor side you know
we can see the loss ratios uh you know
improving uh for you uh both on a
sequential and annual basis and uh
significant Improvement very
specifically on the third party side uh
so just uh just just if you could give
some commentary in terms of you know
what's happening over here how is the
competitive intensity and I believe we
have gained market share in this quarter
in both the
segments yeah so nin I think uh you're
right I think uh clearly uh over the
last last uh few years if You' have seen
I think we have been slightly selective
in the way we have been writing the
risks and therefore to that extent that
has kind of stood Us in times of uh
reflection on the combined outcomes um
having said that I think obviously what
where what we are seeing right now is U
therefore U renewed opportunities in the
way we can write risks and that's
reflective also in terms of the increase
in the market share that we have seen
relative to 9 months of last year
uh generally if you see I think we have
been able to see particularly let's say
in this particular quarter uh between
new and renewal I think largely the
growth has been more or less similar
when you look at at a category level and
therefore we continue to look for
opportunities in each of Private Car two
wheeler CV and broadly if you look at
the mix it's in line with what we have
normally seen over uh prior periods uh
on the loss experience specifically nin
I think this is something that we keep
speaking about um obviously when we kind
of uh write or maybe risk select the
portfolio we have an ultimate loss
experience that we kind of uh go with an
assumption at the time of writing the
risk and over a period of time I think
given the fact that we have generally
been prudent SL conservative in our loss
estimates as the loss experiences starts
to develop I mean we can see this not
just for uh this year across years we
have been able to see let's say
favorable loss development and that
starts to getting that starts to get
reflected on the numbers um as we kind
of see across different Financial
periods uh so that's where we are but
broadly if you ask me I think in terms
of the overall loss ratio range that
I've kind of spoken about even in the
past and again as I keep saying uh it's
always better to look at motor as a
category rather than looking at own
damage and third party uh independently
and the range that we have spok about
running overall motor uh in that range
of 65 to 67 I think that's broadly the
range that we believe uh we should
continue to see as an outcome in terms
of the portfolio experience so that's
where we are um and uh and and the
positive news is I think some of the
market participants possibly who had
kind of gone quite aggressive uh in the
past uh you can clearly see most of
those companies when you look at their
individual month-on-month growth numbers
clearly there is a there has been a
element of calibration that has happened
and that's also reflective in the
outcomes that these companies had to
exhibit in some of their combined ratio
outcomes so so that's where we are we
continue to be uh cautious in building
the book and so far as the ethos on uh
writing or selecting the portfolios
continues to remain the same as in we
will keep looking for a sustained basis
an economic output uh which we think
think will be viable from a longer term
perspective no absolutely and also the
thing is uh in our mindset I me we will
do what makes sense to US market share
of course this year looks better but uh
uh we also exper the market maybe almost
four quarters back in terms of why our
market share is where it is so it's more
of an
outcome uh of how multiple factors uh
work it's not something uh that we Chase
you know
this it's more outcome and as in when it
makes us look good it's family driven by
an ecosystem development uh as we
continue to pursue what we believe makes
sense for
us and and the Delta this quarter or you
know the the much lower you know loss
ratio in TP this quarter uh you could it
be uh you know uh maybe because of
better releases this quarter so again as
we keep saying I think TP again I have
spoken in numerous occasions even in the
past right I think given that it's
obviously and all of you understand uh
you all have been tracking us pretty
much for a very long period of time uh
so and this is clearly a book which is
much more longtail in terms of L
development loss experiences obviously
have to be looked at uh over a period of
time and as I said obviously the level
of prudence that we kind of go with in
terms of our reserving estimates that
stand pretty much intact absolutely no
change change in the philosophy of
reserving and therefore as the portfolio
actually starts to experience outcomes
you could see let's say some of the
releases play out at different periods
it could be in a particular quarter it
could be in a particular Financial year
but on overall basis which is why if you
look at our reserving triangle now that
you also have a specific triangle
outcome in the context of third party as
well and there again you will see
consistently for us there are small
amount of favorable loss developments
that we have seen over years this is
again not just for one quarter or one
year or uh two years it's across
Financial periods that we have been able
to see some small amount of uh favorable
development and that and hence to that
extent the the approach to reserving
will continue in terms of a favorable
loss development and that's how we have
been kind of going about uh risk
selection as I talked about and just
finally uh in this backdrop uh you know
do we uh really sort of now expect uh uh
tariff
third party Tarik this year so there
again you know well industry is
expecting it for last uh few years and
uh it's not something which we control
uh the answer to this is yes we do
expect the hike but can it can can it
come can it not is something which will
uh come from the regulator as well as Mo
the way TV prices decided so but we do
believe yes it's been 3 to four years
and there might be possibly a hike at
least which you'll get for next
financial
year sure thank you very much and all
the best thank you thank you thanks
thank you ladies and gentlemen in order
to ensure that the management is able to
answer queries from all participants
please restrict your questions to two at
a time you may join back the queue for
followup
questions next question is from the line
of PES Jen from mtila loal please go
ahead
yeah hi uh congrats on a very good set
of numbers uh just you know just harping
gopal on this point on the loss ratio on
the uh motor side again uh uh so you
were mentioning that for the motor as a
piece we should be looking at a loss
ratio of 65 to
67% uh but we are way below that
currently so would you still say that
you
know the the fer number would be in that
range or we should be that's more of a
longer term loss ratio that you would be
looking at uh that's my first question
uh second is on the health loss ratio uh
could you give the give the granularity
on you know how much was the retail
Health loss ratio and how much was the
employer employee uh loss ratio um and
uh just on this you know on the fire
piece you mentioned that uh there could
be you know price hike and so so so why
would that be because your loss ratio
outcomes seems to be pretty uh
controlled at
50.1% uh yeah that would be my question
perfect so maybe I go to the reverse
sequence uh so let me start with the
commercial line um so again PR I think
all of you understand that commercial
lines in general is a relatively High
exposure your portfolio so therefore to
that extent uh you can obviously see
experiences which could be relatively
with low frequency High sity outcomes
and therefore again in a given period
you can obviously see experiences on
loss numbers which could be
significantly adverse or maybe at the
same time the portfolio will logically
kind of in case if you don't have large
number of catastrophic events then what
you normally expect as attritional
losses is what how the portfolio will
develop um I think clearly you have seen
not just in the Indian market I think
across the globe you have clearly seen
increased incidences of some of these
catastrophic events impacting insurers
reinsurers customers at large and
therefore clearly when you look at the
overall portfolio outcome from a market
standpoint I think it's leading to an
outcome where the experiences from a
let's say from a reinsurance standpoint
may not be necessarily in that sense
viable at the level of pricing that they
have given to the market at large so
hence
given the fact that some of these events
are more frequent more in numbers there
is obviously a need for the entire
market across stakeholders to look at
what should be the level of price that
you should kind of offer for this
selection uh equally in the past for
example you would have seen periods of
very long periods of soft pricing as
well so that's how the nature of the uh
business is you will obviously see
through various price Cycles at at
sometimes you will obviously as I said
experience soft price
currently is a regime where maybe
because of these increased incidences
you will see some bit of hardening in
price and hence at least which is where
we we are kind of coming from um the
expectation is at least so far as the uh
quarter 4 and and more importantly the
April 1 renewals which will largely be
the where bulk of the corporate renewals
will happen we do expect the overall
Market to be far more uh sensible in so
far as pricing those risks are concerned
so that's where we are and that's that's
that's what we believe from an overall
positive sentiment uh to your point on
the health loss breakdown as what every
quarter we keep asking for this uh split
uh I think on the corporate Health which
is the ghi segment again I'll give the
quarter three numbers for the both the
segments first which is Corporate health
and then retail inity so for corporate
Health quarter three of last year that
number was
93.1 that number for this quarter 3 is
at 97 .2 and Retail Indemnity numbers
last year was 66% which is down to about
65% on a 9mon basis again in the same
sequence corporate Health last year was
95.8 which is currently about
97.7 and the retail inity numbers which
was 65.6 for 9 months last year that
number stands at about
69.1% uh but more than let's say some of
these numbers in general I think what we
have seen is uh uh I think pretty much
we do see uh maybe some continuation of
uh increased incidences of claims
playing out uh in the context of uh uh
some of the in the health segment
specifically and therefore in line with
what we had spoken even in quarter one
we said we will obviously observe for
the development of this increased
incidences over the next few quarters uh
so that's where we are and in that
context is where the numbers are for the
health loss numbers to your last point
on U more
I think the range that we kind of spoke
about at 65 to 67 you're absolutely
right I think that's obviously the
preferred range at which we would want
to kind of run the book again not just
over one or two year Horizon that's
something that we would want to kind of
look at it over a much more longer term
play having said that I think obviously
in now when it comes to specific
Financial periods it could be purely a
function of what kind of mix of business
that you write U and again we have
discussed this in the past you
particularly when it comes to new motor
that typically comes with a relatively
low loss outcome but possibly a slightly
higher cost of acquisition but equally
on the flip side when you kind of start
to Source more of the renewal or let's
say the older book that invariably comes
with a slightly higher loss outcomes but
obviously a lower cost of acquisition so
that's how we manage the overall
portfolio in the way how we see the
market opportunity but over a medium to
long term I think the range that we are
comfortable with to operate with will be
between that 65 7 67% for motor as a
category got that any price X
contemplating in the health
segment I think that's something that we
keep looking for PR and uh and we have
and we have not shied away from taking a
price change uh you would recollect
again slightly going back to some of our
conversations even in the past um if you
were to go back maybe almost four years
back quarter 3
2021 um at that point of time we did
affect an average price increase of
roughly about 8% of the overall renewal
book uh and then roughly about one and
half two years thereafter again uh we
had kind of expected a price increase
which ranged anywhere between uh 20 to
22% so in general I think again on the
retail inity book specifically again we
have spoken about the fact that the
range that we are comfortable on running
the book is a loss ratio of around that
range between 65 to 70% more towards I
would say slightly on the highest higher
end of the range uh and at this point of
time I think as you would have seen the
outcome largely is kind of playing out
within the range that we are comfortable
with but having said that I think if the
portfolio warrants any kind of a price
division we will not shy away from
taking
one thank you thank you thank you
participants are requested to restrict
to two questions please we have our next
question from the line of sanet Goda
from avenders Park please go
ahead yeah thank you for the opportunity
so gopal you said that you want to work
motor TP on motor loss ISO in the of 60
to 65 if I take at the other end for
motor TP at 65 is it fair to assume that
in Q4 um the loss ratios in motor TP
will be more 70 70 to 75 compared to
what you have reported 60.1 uh for 9
months fi25 so that's that's a fair
assumption to make to to remain
conservative with respect to motor TP
reserving again I I mean just for the
sake of uh rate rating I will keep
saying that uh um I would always urge
all of you to look at numbers more over
longer term Horizon particularly for
motor third party uh it would be
completely in that sense when I when I
use this to say that ideally quarters
will have multiple factors to it um as I
just mentioned one factor would be in
terms of uh the kind of business mix
that we see as an opportunity so that by
itself will determine what the loss
ratio outcome could be U and as I said
we keep looking for the outcome of the
loss development of the book that we
have written in the past and this is not
just something that we do at a
particular point this is something that
we keep evaluating every quarter um and
that would be true even for quarter 4 um
and in case if in any of the past book
reflect something better in terms of
outcome then obviously to that extent
you will see some of the uh impact play
out even in quarter 4 as well uh so
hence uh I think rather than talking
about a point estimate or a point number
for a particular period it's better that
we keep looking at which is where I said
the medium to long-term range on motor
as a category uh because again I think
this is something that all of you
understand it's always in that sense
given the fact that motor own damage is
free to price motor third party is fixed
in tariff better to look at motor as a
category rather than trying to even
split between motor home damage and
third party and hence just to kind of
rate rate medium to long-term range that
we are comfortable on running the book
will be between 65 to 67%
got it and and the see see you reported
uh one2 on 1 byn uh and and 102.8 on if
you exclude 1 byn so so the management
guidance was to end up with 102 for fi25
and probably 101.5 for the fourth
quarter so so even factoring a bit of
negative impact from 1 byn do you still
continue to maintain that guidance to
play out for the full year and and and
if I take Exit as 101.5 for the fourth
quarter should we fairly assume that is
the number which will be there to for
526 and and last and the second thing is
that if you can break down the exact
growth of motor into new and old vehicle
the way you did it last
time yeah so maybe I think I'll give you
the numbers for uh new and old this is
again I'm just kind of giving you for
quarter three uh so new was uh again 9.5
which is what I just mentioned in
response to one of the calls largely the
numbers were similar uh 99.5% growth for
new and almost a similar number of 99.3%
for the old so as a category the overall
growth was
9.4% okay and on the guidance part sank
that you spoke about uh clearly as we
had put across as to where we want to
finish the whole year uh at that point
of time uh there was no visibility that
one by will come and when such changes
happen the configuration of product
which we procure from the market also
can go through
transformation uh there's no reason to
believe that directionally we are not
there but at the same time we also have
to evaluate what the opportunity com
through so it's a combination of all
these aspects that will uh decide the
way forward it's early days is the first
quarter where the industry and us are
giving numbers which are on a one by
basis and the strange part is the
configuration where the first six months
are not on 1 by n and this quarter is 1
by n So to that extent it will uh it
will play out over the course of time
and the industry uh performance which we
spoke about and I said has moved to 113
uh whereas it was 111 so it's kind of
relatively got worsened off so all of
these factors will also weigh but what
we also stay committed is besides the
combine the Roe range that we want to
operate which we spoke about it uh when
we have met up so it's a com
which will keep keeping us excited in
terms of doing selection
also okay perfect that's it from my side
thank you thanks thank you next question
is from the line of nides Jen from
investtech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity the
first question is on this 1 byn has the
impact has been passed on to the
distributor and uh so are they also
getting Commission on a yearly basis and
uh do you expect any impact on the
business growth because of that
uh the answer is yes it's Regulatory and
whatever needs to be done it's done so
it will be also taken where the nut
commission payment will happen to the
distributor uh as far as growth is
concerned uh there is an overarching
impact in terms of long-term product
being sold but internally from an our
organization perspective the economic
value that comes in selling uh the
long-term product stays intact so we
continue to pursue uh in the market uh
selling long product the accounting part
of it will emate as when it happens
and so this I think I think the only
thing that I just add to what sanjie
rightly said I think uh uh this is the
first quarter uh and and therefore to
that extent the market practices will
also see an evolution um in terms of
some of these changes uh uh that gets
played out so for example when uh 6
years back when the regulator had
mandated let's say third party mandatory
for 3 years 5 years uh in between there
were changes uh in terms of the product
construct to get motor uh line of
business recognized on a 1 byn
prescription similar to what you see for
the rest of the lines as we speak today
uh so those practices obviously kind of
evolve over a period of time and hence
we will obviously watch the market
developments very very closely um
obviously I think the the intent when
you look at it from a regulatory
standpoint I think is very very positive
uh in the way they have kind of uh
wanted this particular change and
therefore our practices will be very
clear to make sure that uh we clearly
kind of meet regulatory expectations but
obviously we will keep a very close
watch on Market developments as well and
keep kind of taking actions
corresponding to that yeah and also if I
was a distributor and if I'm able to do
a long-term Health there is no reason
because it is one by n that should go
through a
change what you're not getting in one
year on the front end business you will
get over three years so there's an
annuity income uh that will Pro over a
period of time so there is there can be
a shortterm thought process if you're
not getting it you may not want to
pursue with it hopefully better FS will
prevail and they will also look at
economic value and go ahead and sell
long term uh as always
required uh sure uh uh second question
is on the reinsurance uh the retention
ratio has increased quite materially
this quarter uh to 82% uh so is there
any change in strategy with respect to
reinsurance
so honestly there is
no so if you ask us our insurance
program typically gets decided at the
beginning of the year I think as what we
have mentioned earlier as well uh and
again purely it's it's a function of uh
what is a split between mix of corporate
mix of retail and within that uh if you
recollect in the past we have spoken
about let's say in the context of Health
for example on health Indemnity as a
line of business we have always operated
without in that sense leave aside the
obligatory which is true for everyone in
the market but other than the obligatory
reinsurance we don't have any other
reinsurance requirements from a health
inity standpoint on health benefit as a
category not just again this year across
years we have obviously kind of operated
on a reinsurance structure um and hence
and if you recollect particularly not
just against this quarter this year in
general I think the health benefit
segment has seen an impact on growth and
therefore to that extent that will
obviously have an impact on the net
retention numbers so that's one second
for whatever it is even quarter three
does have an element of corporate
business as well it's not that corporate
business comes down to zero and there
the approach for us again if you look at
it over a 9 month basis we have been
very very selective largely we have
tried to kind of hold on to maintaining
market share in that particular category
and given the fact that that particular
business is slightly in that in s
subdued that again kind of contributes
to the overall retention numbers but if
you see the overall retention number the
way we kind of look at it I mean on the
net premium to uh gross premium I think
at least if you look at it on a 9 Monon
basis at least the number stands at
roughly I'm talking about the current
year uh if you look at it on a even with
the 1 byn uh impact uh I think the
retention numbers will be roughly at
about 72% I think that's where we are
and to answer your point no change in
the reinsurance strategy nothing
specific it's not a case where we had an
element of reinsurance for the first six
months or something and suddenly we have
decided to kind of change our approach
to reinsurance um nothing of no
significant change therein and the other
aspect is the bulk of the reinsurance
renewal conversations will now happen in
quarter four for the next financial
year okay and last question is on claims
inies I'm sorry to interrupt NES can you
please join back the que okay sure thank
you sure sure thanks we have a next
question from the line of jant kot from
Jeff please go ahead uh thank you for
the
opportunity asset mode please J not very
clear thank you for the opportunity uh
first question is on the competitive
scenario uh given that we are
approaching the E Glide path uh last
couple of uh quarters uh how do you see
it play out over the next year and
specifically the impact on that is
having on Group Health and fire uh and
what would be our sort of stance in in
in case it intensifies uh going into the
next say four to six quarters uh that's
the first question I'll come back with
the second one so just clearly on the
our stand has been pretty clear on that
uh we continue to operate within the um
guidelines and there is no reason under
any circumstances we would like to
violate that uh as in when we see
intensity building up uh we will choose
withdraw rather than participate in that
kind of uh you know business intensity
another point is that the regulator has
taken certain action so in terms of
expecting companies which are not within
the um guidelines to fall in line uh
with that there is possibility that it
will get disciplined and will not see a
Russian pricing if you see business
lines like ghi and some others uh
further going low we would rather than
participant so we have absolute clarity
as a team uh to let go what is not
making commercial sense for
us uh so do you see this uh playing out
in the claims of your competition and
then by when do you expect some more
rationality on the pricing in these
products uh any any timeline see we we
no one to judge in terms of what
everyone else will do but that being
said uh we did speak about where fire
went and where fire is expected to be so
anything with go below a threshold uh
will tend to autocorrect itself uh as
it's not
viable it will play out look it will
play out it's not that it will not play
out but there's a point of time when
others will and we respect that we like
to fall in line for UF and manage this
subsequently as in when things grow up
but by share presumption is that each
one of us who operates in the industry
wants to run the business in a
profitable Manner and better sense will
Prevail over a period of
time okay so second question is on IFRS
uh we know we haven't we know we've
guided at least indicated on some
improvement on the combined ratio uh but
it's been uh almost three four quarters
now uh any any more uh disclosures or
any anything that you have gone back and
and can help us understand what could be
the possible impact so on Al Forest
obviously as in the rules come in we
will fall in line uh there is
there is no question of the not falling
in line they've also spoken about the
overall benefit it can have on account
of discounting of reserving and also def
you know expenses coming into play it
will aminate in time to come but one
fundamental thing which we all have to
understand is that this is just mode of
accounting right the economic value that
gets given whether it's B by whether
it's IFRS all of it is part of the
process in which manner you will do the
accounting of it the business being
sought the long-term value that is to
get created they all remain similar you
can project this numbers in multiple
manner it doesn't change how you want to
operate it's not that IFRS will change
the manner in which you want to do
business they still will like to do what
we are pursuing at this point of time so
there is excitement of that coming
through and we will be more than happy
in fact we are very clear to say that
why only large PA everybody in the
industry should start publishing on IFRS
basis any indicative timeline by when
will you to join back the que please as
we have other participants waiting thank
you thank
you next question is from the line of
subaman Aer from Morgan Stanley please
go
ahead uh hi uh thanks for the
opportunity uh I had an accounting
question so on slide number 15 you have
given basically the comparison between
uh profits excluding 1 byn and without
in with 1 byn um and U you have given
the gdpi and Pat so uh Pat is actually
higher under the with one by impact so
is it fair to conclude that your uh
commissions are lower because of defs
under with 1 byn method and that's what
is resulting in the higher
profits again uh uh this is again which
is why I kind of responded to say that
uh the prescription under one by need
not necessarily be uh in terms of
outcome uh go in the direction of only
an increase in profits uh because again
this will be a function of uh what kind
of business mix that you Source uh what
is the kind of reinsurance structures
that you may have in practice uh and
what is the kind of acquisition cost
that you kind of relate to with respect
to sourcing any of those businesses so
there are multiple factors which will
drive let's say an outcome when you look
at it from a transition to a 1 byn slash
without a 1 byn uh uh outcomes now
talking specific in the context of
quarter 3
I think obviously this has been a
quarter where we were just kind of
talking about in general I think the
credit link dispersement uh across
financial institutions have clearly been
muted and obviously to that extent and
we have been one of the key writers of
some of those risks and that's an area
where I said we have always been
historically operating also with the
reinsurance structur the fact that the
business growth has been relatively
subdued obviously that does have an
impact both in terms of growth in
premiums and therefore correspondingly
the impact that it has I mean when you
look at 1 byn effectively the
prescription is to say that whatever
acquisition cost that you incur you
defer it over the contract period
similarly if there's an element of
reinsurance income that you may have
that is something again you defer it
over the policy contract so in a quarter
if you do see businesses where you
already had an element of insurance
Arrangement and if that business gets
subdued then therefore the relative
impact in outcome will not necessarily
be the same as compared to a line of
business for example in quarter 3 we
also have contracts of other lines of
businesses where we don't have a
reinsurance Arrangement but there's a
cost of acquisition and by this very
inherent nature of a transition to 1 byn
the cost gets deferred there is nothing
in terms of income for us to kind of
defer over the policy period leave aside
the obligatory that's a very very small
component so that's the reason why you
see an outcome for quarter three in
terms of profits to be higher than what
you would have normally reported on a
without one by approach now this can
change going ahead if let's say the
proportion of mix of businesses undergo
a change in terms of the various factors
that I spoke the outcome could be either
reversed you could possibly see a
situation of neutrality in terms of no
change in profits or equally you could
see maybe an outcome similar to what
you're seeing for quarter 3 this year so
lot of moving Parts uh so hence to that
extent very difficult to say attribute
uh any specific reasons but quarter
three this is the reason it has been
more more businesses which are long-term
hard the ones where there are only cost
of Acquisitions to be amored but
relatively there are no reinsurance
commissions to
be thanks that's very clear um wish you
all the best thank you than thank you
next question is from the line of maduka
Lada from noama wealth management please
go
ahead uh hi congratulations on a very
good set of numbers uh couple of
questions from me first I see a very
sharp increase in commission uh cost now
uh can you explain what has led to that
and second is um in the new 1 byn uh now
you know that that's the way we will be
reporting numbers so what should our uh
guidance be in terms of you know uh exit
in Q4 for combine ratio and also then uh
what are we looking at uh uh for the
next few years so yeah you know some
help on that would be uh very very
useful yeah so mukar again um I mean I
will always keep again kind of urging
all of you to look at uh numbers more on
a combined ratio of prescription rather
than even looking at uh breakdown of
that combined into loss ratio and let's
say maybe the expense ratio and within
that you are maybe asking the question
which is more further breakdown on uh
commission numbers corresponding to that
um so so that so given the nature of the
business that we have you will obviously
see a mix of outcome as I just mentioned
Q3 in specific uh I think you have seen
on bit say for whatever corporate
business that we used to write in the
past that particular part of the
business has been muted and therefore to
that extent you will obviously see a
relatively lower cost of uh acquisition
uh which otherwise would have been there
had that particular growth of Commercial
Business been there in quarter 3 and
hence the large part of quarter 3 are
businesses which are fundamentally
driven in so far as the retail line of
opportunity is concerned and to quarter
three in general if you see it's a
period of festive season uh so when you
kind of put both of this together you
will obviously find an outcome in terms
of even in the context of just the
commission numbers or let's say the
commission ratio you will obviously
possibly see an increase therein but at
the end of the day even as what Sanji
mentioned I think for us
I think what what what is something that
we are very very conscious of is to make
sure that we run the overall operations
at an expense of management which cannot
kind of exceed 30% so that's that's a
guard guard rail for us is something
that we are very very conscious of and
two and more importantly I think for us
we will obviously keep looking for
outcomes in the form of combined ratios
on businesses and at the end of the day
we are all here to give as what we have
put also in the opening remarks which is
a sustained uh return return on uh
capital for stakeholders so that's
equally important from an Roe outcome is
something that again we are very very
conscious of I think the range that we
have spoken about is to be within that
range of 16 to 18% and as things it
starts to improve relative to the market
obviously we would want to see that
getting better as well so those are
those are guard ra within which we kind
of operate with and hence to that extent
I would again urge each of you to look
at outcomes with some of these uh uh
guard rails as a benchmark and to your
point on what would be the outcome on
quarter 4 combined and maybe let's say
as we head into the next financial year
I think sanjie already kind of responded
to that in response to one of the
earlier questions I think again as we
keep saying let's say when we look at
quarter four two factors one we
obviously have to wait and see how the
environment place so to that EXT that's
a variable second I think we will have
to see how the market responds I think
what we have said our our combin will
again be uh in relation to the industry
outcomes at least the first half seeks
to indicate that the market is slightly
more adverse uh compared to 111 it's at
about 113 so we'll wait and see how
quarter three numbers are for the other
players in the market and corresponding
to that is how our own quarter 4
outcomes will play out but what we are
conscious of I think in all fairness
when we look at maybe just the return on
uh Equity to stakeholders I think the
broad comfort that we can give you is we
should definitely end the year within
that range of about 16 to 18% and as we
head into the next year the approach to
writing risk will still the same and
then we will keep looking for profitable
opportunity I'll give you a small
perspective so probably you'll get a
better understanding of what gopal also
is talking about it if you look at a
last year number even before that
commercial business for us was uh
clearly you know doing a very good
growth numbers and you know that
commercial business overarchingly Works
in a combined ratio Which is far lower
so when they got when we started working
on the planning for this year itself we
had a believe that commercial line per
se will remain secular on the
contribution which is what gopal also
you know alluded in this conversation I
think stand it's not commercial line
which
has grown but the retail line of
business which is you know we're talking
about retail Indemnity that a motor and
business which has given us growth and
when the configuration changes it's
forent to understand that the combine
ratio will also change but the overall
value that we want to give the
stakeholder may not get impacted at all
so the so the obsession with combine
ratio I do understand from your angle
but how we look at businesses has to be
understood in a far more comprehensive
manner to give a particular level of
targeted Roe there will be changes if
you struck to the same plan maybe would
we wouldn't have done what is required
on retail and still stuck to a low
growing growth so we would have done a
much
lesser uh Top Line as well as sh a
better combine but it would not have
served the purpose so the point point
that gopal keeps making is look at the
business in a far more comprehensive
manner we will have to stay agile in
terms of what opportunities gets
provided we do not want to while we do
give guidance and we did speak about it
we don't want to get ourselves tied down
because we have had X combined number we
let go an opportunity which will serve
us much better in long term it's an
overarching thought which I want to put
across and why we'll have to also real
time change our plans as the market uh
uh you know forces us to react to it
understood so got it I'll I'll come back
in the que the yeah thank you thank you
thank you m next question is from the
line of Rishi junjun Wala from iifl
institutional equities please go ahead
yeah thank you I'm sorry to interrupt
rishy I request you to restrict to one
question please thank you okay I'll make
it a long one thank
you
said so uh so just you know first um you
know on the investment leverage right so
if we look at it it's already down to
3.7 77 for us and uh there has been a
sharp decline in the last 6 months and
this is despite the fact that you know
I'm assuming that motor vehicle act
related benefits haven't really
completely played out as yet so just
wanted to understand your thoughts in
terms of uh you know with or without uh
that implementation on a pan India basis
where do you see uh the investment uh
leverage uh uh you know stable out or
stabilized and a and a related question
to that is um you know 2 three years ago
we had given up this uh 20% Roe and 100%
combined ratio uh Target in order to
ensure that we are not missing out on
growth opportunities given that we are
now at 20% Roes and uh uh combined
ratios are you know trending closer to
100 I mean we're still 200 bips away um
do you think there could be a
recalibration to that Target
um you know in the medium
term so uh so Rishi let me take again
the reverse sequence uh uh so I think if
you ask us uh the the the uh narrative
in terms of our intent to keep looking
for profitable growth opportunities
Remains the Same so therefore to that
extent um do we stand committed to
staying within that return on Equity
objective of course I think that pretty
much kind of stays intact
um and that's the range why I kind of
talked about uh in the medium term given
the level of combine we should be kind
of getting to an outcome which could be
between 16 to 18% the reason why I'm
saying this is because uh you will still
appreciate the fact that we don't want
to
lose opportunities for investment in
areas which will Propel growth for uh in
the future uh so that's something that
we are very very conscious of and
therefore these Investments which we
have been kind of speaking through even
in the past will entail an up renting of
expense in the pnl and that by itself
when you look at it from an just from an
Year's outcome it will possibly look at
maybe an Roe which may not be equal
exactly to 20% for that matter of fact
but but these are investments which we
think is something that we should make
at this point of time the uh the effect
of which will play through maybe over
the next 2 three years uh but if you ask
us again the point that we keep saying I
think uh the econom objective in terms
of what we want to write clearly is
within that range of Ro objective that I
responded in response to one of the
earlier questions same thought process
on combin I think uh the lens with which
we look at each of the business
opportunity again not just any
particular line across lines I think the
lens that we kind of apply is obviously
combined and equally ultimately the uh
returns that you would kind of fetch to
stakeholders for the capital that is
being infused so obviously that both of
this doesn't have not fundamentally
changed and we kind of stand committed
to the range that we have kind of spoken
through uh but all of this have to be
looked at in the context of how the
market operates um and hence to that
extent uh this may be something that you
will see playing out over long term
assuming the market start responding
sensibly but uh but at times in case if
the market uh responds more aggressively
uh uh in terms of competition then to
that extent maybe some of this metries
will possibly get postponed by a year or
two too so that's where we are um on the
first point the investment leverage I
think again um this is again if you look
at the way the leverage gets computed
obviously there is a numerator which is
the investment assets and the
denominator which is let's say net worth
U and then investment assets is
obviously in the context of the various
Investments some of these Investments
are carried at a market value and these
are Point estimates at a point of time
and as you would have seen particularly
since you're looking at the numbers on a
quarter three basis for example uh we
have seen obviously particularly Equity
markets relatively exhibiting a slightly
more subdued sentiment and in that
context I think if you look at maybe the
market to market position that you would
have had of the book as at September
relative to as of December obviously at
a point of time that number would have
seen us seen us seen a decline uh so
that would have some some impact when
you look at the investment leverage
second I think again as what we have
been speaking there has also been a
relative slowdown in growth uh in in
general for us and that by itself
clearly also contributes to the overall
uh available cash flows and that has
also had an impact in the overall uh
investment leverage and third I think
again clearly when you look at um
particularly for some of the commercial
lines which generally is very very
profitable that's also been a segment
where we have not seen as much of growth
as what one would have expected so all
these factors is where we are on The
Leverage but as the environment improves
we should start seeing the leverage kind
of coming back and also the small thing
uh thanks goal is that that motor
vehicle act that you refer to receive is
a faster intimation then they there'll
be a lower investment leverage not
higher so that's one small thing it's
more driven by cash flow and
configuration in terms of the nature of
business that comes through ironically
as much I don't want to but if you have
a growth of P also that buget that Isom
of a Networth will go up and that itself
will lead to investment leverage going
down I mean it's more mathematical in
that sense what I'm saying but there
multiple think will go in uh it's again
an outcome we do understand the value of
Leverage in your mind but we right
business in terms of what makes sense
and this comes out as an outcome we do
it's not that we don't look at cash flow
but that is not the reason why we end up
writing certain businesses or eliminate
any
businesses okay thank you so much all
the thank you thank you request
participants to restrict to one question
please we'll take the next question from
the line of ainash Singh from MK Global
please go
ahead yeah uh thanks for the opportunity
great set of numbers just one question
again coming to that I mean I recall
your kind of uh focus on combine not
scale claims and expenses but more on
the expenses if you put together I mean
uh one that is regulator now kind of
looking for any kind of a change with
their um targets because the rule of
game has been changed in between uh with
this one byn account
and if you can help us I mean even on a
kind of a commission plus opic basis
which are the business lines for
particularly that is seeing a bit of I
would say intensified payouts or
competition on in terms of payout that
is leading to this overall Opex
including commission
increase thank yeah so so again uh on
the on the uh on the point on uh e
ainash uh uh so uh so the first at this
point of time I think obviously I don't
think the regulator is contemplating
anything specific in terms of uh any
change in the thought process I think U
as a regulator I think what they're
looking for is uh to make sure that the
overall industry operates within a
defined threshold uh and at this point
of time that number stands at about 30%
or 35% as the case may be uh and there
is this has been just put into practice
maybe since the last one year or so so
hence to that extent to expect anything
suddenly changing uh given even the
given the change that they have put in
the context of one byn or thereabout at
least that's something that's not within
our knowledge in terms of whether the
regulator is looking for any specific
changes to be made so at this point of
time the limit of 30 or 35 stands intact
having said that I think what we at
least understand uh from the market is
uh the regulator obviously keeping a
very very close watch on making sure
that the larger market players continue
to make make need to make sure that they
run their overall operations at an e
Which is less than 30 or 35 as the case
may be and if you look at basis public
uh disclosure of uh Financial outcomes
still there are a large number of
players who even on an fi2 24 basis have
exceeded the threshold and clearly from
Market we understand that the regulator
has asked each of these companies to
come out with a plan of action to make
sure that they are able to kind of come
come within the threshold so that is
where we are uh we don't think there is
going to be anything immediate in so far
as change in the expectations on meeting
the limits on expense of management is
concerned from a market
perspective your second point on uh what
are the business lines that invariably
kind of contributes to let's say a high
expense of management again multiple
factors uh so for example the point that
I made saying that if you make any uh
investments in opportunities for the
future now that entails a cost that will
be a part of my expense of management
numbers today so that will put that will
increase the uh ratio second in terms of
the mix of business that you write which
is what I explained earlier if I'm
writing let's say an old relatively new
portfolio on the motor side that
invariably comes with maybe a low loss
ratio High expense so that will let the
result in in higher expense numbers
and the third will be again given the
fact that we are driving a lot more on
retail Health uh so that invariably
comes with a slightly higher cost of
acquisition so multiple moving parts and
that's the reason why I keep saying look
at more on combined as compared to just
the expense Rao
numers okay clear thank you thank you
thank you ladies and gentlemen that was
the last question for today I now hand
the call over to Mr sanjie Man for
closing comments over to you sir great I
think uh thank you so much for joining
it it's always a pleasure and your
questions also give us tremendous
Clarity we look forward to interacting
with uh each one of you over the course
of next few weeks uh look forward to
your support as always and have a great
year ahead thank you so much bye-bye
thank Youk you on behalf of icsa Lombard
General Insurance company that concludes
this conference thank you for joining us
and human AR disconnect